bigscoots.com 2019-04-30

# BigScoots

**Last Updated:** Thursday, February 28, 2019. 12:00 CST

### BigScoots Privacy Policy

BigScoots.com (“BigScoots”) has developed this privacy statement to validate our commitment to confidentiality to all our customers and users who use BigScoots’ online services (“Services”). These services consist of domain purchase, transfer and management, shared web hosting, reseller web hosting, managed wordpress hosting, virtual private servers, hybrid servers, data backups, dedicated servers and colocation.

This privacy policy dictates the methods in which BigScoots preserves, maintains and divulges information gathered from its clients and the steps we take to conform to the E.U.-U.S. Privacy Shield Program.

### 1\. Our Commitment to Privacy

BigScoots is committed to crafting long lasting relationships based on trust and transparency. All of us at BigScoots always has and always will do anything reasonably within our power to ensure your right to privacy is preserved. Our services are not directed at anyone under the age of thirteen.

### 2\. Data We Collect

On occasion BigScoots requests and gathers personal information from our clients in a variety of ways. These consist of online data entry forms for ordering products and services, communicating with the BigScoots staff, as well as other instances where users can volunteer their own private information.

The data we gather is undeniably personal and can be used to identify you, which is exactly why we take privacy so seriously and also why it is a necessary evil. Personal information plays a commanding role when conducting business online in a secure manner.

Some of the data gathered can consist but is not limited to: Complete address and location Personal and company web addresses Given name and surname E-mail addresses Telephone numbers Credit card information Other billing information

Although rare, on occasion BigScoots may gather data about how our clients access our services using tracking identifiers which are specific to each client through the use of cookies or other similar means.

### 3\. What Exactly Are Cookies

A cookie can be fundamentally defined as a piece of data that is stored on a clients computer which identifies information about that specific client. BigScoots on occasion can make use of both session identifier cookies as well as persistent cookies. With session identifier cookies once the browser is closed or logged out of, the cookie is automatically erased. A persistent cookie on the other hand is a minor text file that is stored on your hard drive for a prolonged period of time.

By using our services you are agreeing to the overall acceptance of this privacy policy and therefore our use of cookies. At any time feel free to review your browsers help file to gather the instructions necessary to remove these persistent cookies, however please keep in mind they are only being used in the first place to stream line our interaction with you and better our service.

### 4\. Log Files

Similar to most websites out there, BigScoots uses log files for both security and to streamline our services. This is a form of data gathering which may include information such as internet protocol addresses, internet service providers, browser type and versions, referring and exit pages, platforms, date and time stamps, number of clicks for trend analysing as well as gathering very broad demographic information. Similar to the cookie scenario none of the information stored in these log files contain individually distinguishable data.

### 5\. How Does BigScoots Use This Information?

BigScoots may use any of the individually distinguishable data gathered by BigScoots to contact our clients concerning services offered by BigScoots, and to the extent the client has agreed, by trusted business partners, affiliates or independent contractors.

BigScoots may also use any of the gathered data for analysis on the success of our services and advertising efforts. Under no condition other than legal action or our client specifically authorizing such disclosures will BigScoots ever share this information with a third party.

### 6\. Disclosure of Data

Although unlikely and not in the foreseeable future, BigScoots does reserve the right to disclose completely anonymous data to investors and/or possible partners. In this case purely basic information will be disclosed and individually distinguishable data will remain completely private. In the case of BigScoots being sold, the information collected from our clients may be transferred to the new owner(s) under the condition that all individually distinguishable data will remain private.

BigScoots may on occasion interact with a third party consultant, advisor, marketing team or IT professional where it may become necessary to disclose private data. Everything disclosed under these terms will require the third party to treat all data, especially individually distinguishable data with the same concern and respect that BigScoots does. All third parties are prohibited from disclosing such data to any other person or party.

Further, individuals will always have access to their own personal data unless those same individuals have previously requested their data to be removed.

In the context of an onward transfer, BigScoots has responsibility for the processing of personal information it receives under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. BigScoots shall remain liable under the Principles if its agent processes such personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless BigScoots proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

### 7\. Newsletters, Special Offers And Service Updates

On occasion and on no particular schedule our clients may receive details on special offers, general newsletters as well as service updates providing they have agreed to receive this type of communication.

### 8\. Legal Disclaimer

Although BigScoots takes every precaution to maintain your confidentiality, on occasion a need may arise where we can and should disclose personally identifiable information if required by law. These disclosures will only occur if BigScoots has a good-faith belief that such action is necessary or BigScoots is required to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served to BigScoots.

On occasion our clients may also find links to other websites through the BigScoots site or through other correspondence. It is our clients responsibility to be aware that BigScoots cannot control the privacy policies of third parties. Read the privacy policies of websites that collect personally identifiable data thoroughly and be aware of how it can be distributed. This privacy policy as indicated herein is applicable only to the data collected by BigScoots.

### 9\. Data Upkeep

The majority of the data gathered by BigScoots is saved indefinitely and for security and data preservation reasons may be saved on more than one database that may be directly or indirectly supported by BigScoots.

Though impossible to absolutely guarantee that misuse, abuse, adjustment or loss to the data will not occur over time, BigScoots makes every possible effort within reason to avert such incidences.

### 10\. Your Responsibility 

As with any personal account information you alongside the rest of our clientele are responsible for maintaining the integrity of the login information you are given. This information can consist of but is not limited to user-names and passwords that give access to personal and private information. A valuable life lesson many of us learn far too late; keep your login information safe and never share it with others. Under no circumstance will BigScoots or any of its employees ask for your login credentials.

It is your personal responsibly while maintaining your data security here at BigScoots to educate yourself on mischievous software and potential scams. Key loggers, viruses and a collection of other scams can seize your information from where you access your BigScoots services. For this reason it is necessary to understand your own risks from personal devices and maintain a high level of security awareness. Additionally, when accessing BigScoots services from foreign devices you should take further precautions and always remember to log out when you are done.

### 11\. Questions, Concerns And Comments

As with any of our policies and services we offer here at BigScoots we are always looking for ways to improve. If there are any questions, concerns or comments please feel free to contact us and let us know what we can do to make your BigScoots experience even better.

Although BigScoots makes a conscious effort to keep our clients in the loop on any changes to this Privacy Policy, it is possible that it can be changed without notice. It is your responsibility to review the policy regularly and communicate any discrepancies you may find.

### 12\. Privacy Shield

BigScoots complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from European Union to the United States. BigScoots has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/list.

In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, BigScoots commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact BigScoots at:

BigScoots, INC. 877-570-3396 abuse@bigscoots.com

BigScoots has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, a panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs).

Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through any of the above channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel.

If your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, you should contact the state or national data protection or labor authority in the jurisdiction where you work. BigScoots agrees to cooperate with the relevant national DPAs and to comply with the decisions of the DPA Panel.

BigScoots’s Privacy Shield compliance is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC).
